Jihye Choi

San Jose, CA • (714) 290-2032

jihye1023@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in /jihyechoi1023 • github.com/jhye1023

Summary

Data analyst with over 6 years of experience in interpreting and analyzing data, and leading implementation of process improvements within the financial industry and a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley Extension. Has strong technical skills to manipulate large data and provide ad hoc reports.

Projects

New York Property Sales:

- Dashboard to show the phenomena and trends of properties sold in New York City using yearly sales information from NYC Open Data.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, HTML, CSS, Tableau and deploying to Heroku.

Tracking the Covid-19 Outbreak:

- Data visualization for the snapshots of confirmed cases, death cases, and mortality rates of Covid-19 in the worldwide and United States.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib, and Seaborn.

Job Search:

- A web application that finds the new opening jobs. Scrape web data and display it on a customized website.
- Tools used: Python, Flask, BeautifulSoup, HTML and CSS

Professional Experience

Open Bank - Los Angeles, CA

07/2015-02/2020

AVP & Accounting Officer

- Executed monthly financial statements including key performance indicators analysis to facilitate executive management decision making.
- Decreased approximately 1 day per month for financial packages processing time by developing Excel worksheets using index-match, and sumifs functions.
- Conducted quarterly forecasting based on historical trends to meet within a 5% variance deviation target versus actual.

US Metro Bank - Garden Grove, CA

09/2013-06/2015

Accounting Supervisor

- Performed month-end processes including journal entries and general ledger reconciliation.
- Conserved about \$7,000 in cost from late fees per year by processing all bills on time.

Education

UC Berkeley Extension

02/2020-08/2020

Certificate, Data Analytics and Visualization

University of California, San Diego

Bachelor of Arts, Economics and Accounting

Skills

Advanced Microsoft Excel • Microsoft Word • Microsoft PowerPoint • VBA • SQL • Python • Tableau